# **Bryant Richards**

Dickson, TN 37055 | 270-752-0842 | brich@codeninja.life Github BryantIT | www.codeninja.life/blog | codeninja.life

## JOB TITLE

Experienced in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React based programming and a background in the service industry. Possess strong skills in project management, team building and management that help teamwork focused business operate effectively. I have always been involved with tech, from high school clubs to tinkering with games and computers, I have always loved it and am thrilled to start my career as a Software Engineer.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Postgresgl, Javascript, React, Redux, GraphQL, Next.js, Node, Material UI, Firebase

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Personal Media Library - Github | Demo

A way to keep track of your personal collection of dvds and books.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Custom search function to allow for live searching of media
- Used serialization to standardize JSON output.
- Extensive use of CSS to create a styled user experience.

# Job Hunt Assistant - Github | Demo

An app to organize the job hunt.

- Used a Rails API back end to store data.
- Used a decorator pattern to structure the JS.
- Made use of asynchronous fetch calls with async/await.
- Used the dataset attribute to grab form input.

## Harry Potter Daily Prophet - Github | Demo

Newspaper staff site for generating newspaper in the style of the Daily Prophet from Harry Potter.

- Used scope to allow filtering of articles by author.
- Used 3rd party authentication for singing up and logging in with 3rd party providers.
- Created custom validations to validate form data.
- Utilized Amazon AWS to allow users to submit and use images.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**KochaSoft, Inc**Systems Developer

Dickson, TN
08/2020 - 01/2021

- Working remotely with a world wide team.
- Front End development utilizing React/Next.js, Material UI and GraphQL for api gueries.
- Agile Environment.
- Developed an LMS for YMCA Quebec.

Mosquito Authority

Dickson, TN
Pest Control Technician

04/2019 - 09/2019

- Working remotely from home ensured all equipment was in working order daily.
- Through continuous study maintained multiple certifications for state compliance.

**Bunzl Distribution**Quality Control

Murray, KY
10/2018 - 04/2019

Inspected outgoing products to ensure accuracy and quality.

## **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School**Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

New York, NY

09/2019 - 05/2020